New Haven Concert Programs
Yale University Music Library
New Haven Concert Programs
1824-1859
Misc. Ms. 300
Yale University Music Library
0.25
(1 box)
Programs of 24 concerts in New Haven between 1824 and 1859
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of 24 programs of concerts held in New Haven from 1824 to 1859. Included are performances by such well-known musicians as the Hutchinson Family Singers, the soprano Jenny Lind, and the violinist Ole Bull.
Concert programs; Concerts -- Connecticut -- New Haven -- 19th century; New Haven (Conn.) -- Social life and customs -- 19th century; Bull, Ole, 1810-1880; Lind, Jenny, 1820-1887; Hutchinson Family (Singers)
- Center Church Choir, 1824 Jun 9
- North Church Choir, 1826 May 2
- Baptist Church, 1826 Jul 17
- North Church Choir, 1828 Sep 9
- Center Church: hymns for the funeral of William Henry Harrison, 1841 Apr 17
- Mr. Braham, song concert, Exchange Saloon, 1842 Mar 4
- Mr. Braham, song concert, Church Street Church, 1842 Apr 5
- Commencement Concert, C.B. Metcalf (choral concert?), 1842 Aug 18
- Signor Cirillo Antognini, vocal and instrumental concert, Saunder's Hall, 1842 Aug 23
- Mr. Wall, the blind harper, vocal and instrumental concert, Exchange Saloon, 1842 Oct 21
- The Hutchinson Family, vocal concert, the Temple, 1844 Apr 22
- James R. Mershon, exhibition of vocal and instrumental music, Centre Church, 1844 Jun 4
- New York Sacred Music Society, Handel's Messiah, Methodist Church, 1846 Aug 18
- Mr. Phoebus, vocal concert, Exchange Saloon, 1848 no date
- Children's Choir, directed by Mr. Phoebus, 1848 Oct 31
- The Seasons (or Juvenile Cantata), North Church, 1848 Nov 1, 2
- Children's Choir, directed by Mr. Phoebus, The Seasons (or Juvenile Cantata), North Church, 1848 Dec 6, 8
- Jenny Lind (no location), 1851? Dec 12
- Singing School for young ladies and children, directed by Mr. Phoebus, Smith's Hall, 1853? Mar 26?
- Wm. Mason's concert, Brewster's Hall, 1854 Oct 16
- Ole Bull, City Hall, 1855 Oct 2
- Union Musical Institute, Lyceum Hall, 1856 Jan 17
- Germania Serenade Band of Boston, Brewster's Hall, 1858 Apr 4
- Mendelssohn Society of New Haven, First Methodist Episcopal Church, 1859 Mar 31
- Germania Serenade Band of Boston, Brewster's Hall, 1859 Jun 13